Guide to the Vietnam War Miscellany, 1965-1989
Vietnam War Miscellany, 1965-1989
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Vietnam war miscellany, 1965-1989
Cornell University, Library, Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Collector
7050
.4 cubic ft.
Pamphlets, clippings, ephemera.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Documents relating to the Vietnam War, collected from various sources.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
U.S. military documents including U.S. Navy Personal Response Office bulletins and pamphlets; brochure from Massachusetts Political Action for Peace; items relating to folklore and folksongs from the U.S. military in Vietnam; brochures about the Women in Military Service Memorial and the Virginia War Memorial; articles, magazines, and newsletters including "Vietnam War Newsletter (1981-1983); Vietnamese tract on U.S. imperialism, "South Vietnam U.S. Defeat Inevitable, by General Van Tien Dung, published by Foreign Languages Publishing House, Hanoi, 1967. Also, copies of letters from Ho Chi Minh to Harry Truman. Also, postage stamps.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. Library. Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, collector.; United States, Navy. Personal Response Office.; Massachusetts Political Action for Peace.; Vietnam War Veterans Archives.
Subjects:
Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975--United States.; Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975--Protest movements.
Places:
United States--History--Vietnamese Conflict, 1961-1975.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Available Copies:
The original letters of Ho Chi Minh to Harry Truman are in the National Archives, Record Groups Nos. 59 and 84.
CONTAINER LIST
- U.S. Military Documents, "Understanding the Americans," U.S. Navy Personal Response Office, "Tet A New Year for Vietnam," U.S. Navy PersonalResponse Office, U.S. Navy Personal Response Project Officer bulletins USAID Project managers, 1971 "PSYOP Policy, Policy Number 71, Bombing Halt," November 2, 1968 JUSPAO Guidances Issue Number 3, June 12, 1965, "U.S. Military Build Up and Problems of the American Presence in Vietnam" JUSPAO Guidances Issue Number 4, July 22, 1965, "Propaganda Approaches to the Presence of Major PAVN Units in South Vietnam" (Box 1, Folder 1)
- "What Can I Do About Vietnam?", Brochure from Massachusetts Political Action for Peace. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Vietnam War folklore items, "General Edward G. Lansdale and the Folksongs of Americans in the Vietnam War," Lydia M. Fish, Journal of American Folklore, Vol. 102, October-November 1989, No. 406 Broadside from the Vietnam Veterans Oral History and Folklore Project Concert program from "Jody's Got Your Cadillac" Program for "Private Expressions/Shared Memories: The Folk Art of Marine Combat Veteran Michael D. Cousino, Sr.," a one-man exhibition, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Donald Harrison, Collector, Pamphlets relating to war memorials including: - Virginia War Memorial - Women in Military Service Memorial Vietnam War Newsletter, 1981-1983 Southeast Asia Bibliography, 1980 Photocopies of articles Air University Review, January/February 1983 - photocopy Military Review, May 1986 - photocopy Vietnam Studies Bulletin, 1981-1982 The Vietnam Veteran, November 1983 Vietnam Catalog, 1987 Vietnam Veterans Review, December 1981, April 1982 Newsweek, December 14, 1981 Parade, May 2, 1982 Clippings, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- DVD of the film "Winter Soldier" with a publicity flyer and postcard, DVD-514 (Box 1)
  Film includes many photographs by Sheldon Ramsdell
- Articles, 1969-1970, 1978, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Southeast Asia bibliography, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Vietnam War Newsletter, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Clippings, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Newsweek, Parade issues, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Vietnam Veterans Review, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Vietnam Studies Bulletin, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Vietnam War Newsletter, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Air University Review, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Vietnam Veteran, Vietnam Catalog issues, 1983, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Military Review, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Winter Soldier, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 12)